Diego Mendes Moreno

Software Engineer - Brazilian, 05/Jan/1991

Vila Madalena - São Paulo / SP - Brazil (open to remote) diegomendesmoreno@gmail.com | +55 11 98279-2215

diegomendesmoreno.github.io | github.com/diegomendesmoreno | inkedin.com/in/diego-mendes-moreno-8246a62a

Profile

I have graduated as an Electronics Engineer and have an MBA in Software Engineering. I have experience developing industrial and web applications. My main skills are related to software development in general, following agile software engineering practices.

Skills

Programming - C, Python

Software Engineering - Git, GitHub, Agile Methodology, Unity/MinUnit (tests), Linux

Languages - Portuguese native speaker - Fluent English - Advanced Spanish - Intermediate French

Soft skills - Continuous learning attitude, customer facing communication, team player

Education

Impacta Tecnologia, São Paulo, SP (Brazil) - 2022 MBA Software Engineering

Centro Universitário da FEI, São Bernardo do Campo, SP (Brazil) - 2015 Bachelor of Electronics Engineering

University of Alabama at Birmingham, Birmingham, AL (USA) - 2013

Bachelor of Electrical Engineering (one-year Student Exchange Program)

• Science without Borders Program sponsored by CAPES (Brazilian government)

Experience

Staff Field Applications Engineer | Renesas Electronics, São Paulo, SP (Brazil)

February 2022 - Present

- Provided support for embedded software development
- Provided support for use and configuration of integrated development environments and software debugging tools
- Delivered technical training sessions and product demos
- Part of a worldwide remote team with a hands-on customer facing role

Embedded Software Engineer | J.Assy, São Paulo, SP (Brazil)

February 2021 - February 2022

- Development of embedded software for precision planting (Agribusiness) products
 - Added a CAN (Controller Area Network) API interface to our vacuum seed meter product to support a new kind of seed sensor (Technologies: C, CAN)
 - Expanded the API interface of a wireless sensor gateway adding new features (Technologies: C, CAN)
 - Developed a Proof of Concept (PoC) IoT project end-to-end of a wireless sensor gateway with Wi-Fi connectivity that monitors sensors through a Web App (Technologies: C, Wi-Fi, Web Server, RESTful API, Javascript, HTML, CSS)

- Developed a PC application with a GUI (Graphical User Interface) to monitor sensors in real time, shows important metrics and generates reports (Technologies: Python)
- Worked to add, refactor and integrate code into a large decentralized codebase
- Working with Agile practices and tools (Jira, Git, BitBucket, Confluence)
- Implemented a version control friendly Documentation practice with Markdown and PlantUML for product docs

Field Applications Engineer | Karimex Componentes Eletrônicos, São Paulo, SP (Brazil) May 2014 - February 2021

- Development of embedded software for 8-bit, 16-bit and 32-bit microcontrollers for various applications
- C and Python development for Embedded Linux
- Embedded Linux customization using the Yocto Project
- Development of graphical user interfaces (GUI) with Qt
- · Active use of Git/GitHub for version control
- Use of IoT Web services (MQTT/HTTP) like Tago.io and AWS
- Experience with Wi-Fi (IEEE 802.11), Bluetooth Low Energy (BLE) and TFT control stacks
- Technical training on embedded systems
- Technical support on embedded systems and power electronics
- Development and delivery of product and prototype demonstrations
- Technical visits in customers
- Electronic component specification and cross reference for various applications

Software Engineer Intern | Itaú Unibanco S.A., São Paulo, SP (Brazil) October 2013 - May 2014

• Development of macros (VBA programming) for automation of spreadsheets

Research Intern | Centro Universitário da FEI, São Bernardo do Campo, SP (Brazil) October 2013 - January 2015

 Software and hardware development of an embedded frequency inverter for UPS (uninterruptible power supply) systems

Research Intern | University of Alabama at Birmingham, Birmingham, AL (USA) May 2013 - July 2013

• Experience using high-performance computing (HPC) to process diffusion tensor imaging (DTI) through Shell commands in a Linux/Unix based system